Francisco Hernández | CV

☐ +56 9 8822 1074 • ☑ fthernan@uc.cl • ❷ https://fthernan.github.io

Summary

Autodidact and passionate about science, arts and interaction design. With a strong background in physics and computer science, my goal is to further research in data analysis & visualization, automated analysis and sensing devices. I look forward to create new software and devices that will improve people's life quality.

Education

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

January 2017

Licentiate (Bachelor) degree in Physics

Thesis: "Preliminary studies of exploding wires in a Plasma Focus"

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Santiago, Chile

Master's degree in Physics

Estimated: July 2020
Thesis: "Development of Particle-in-Cell code using the Implicit Moment Method and Monte-Carlo collisions for

laboratoy plasma simulation"

Academic experience

Research, Teaching.

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Research Assistant in Plasma Laboratory

April 2014 - present

Among the tasks performed is the creation of electronics to control pulsed-power experiments, obtaining & analyzing spectra of plasma emission and realizing various optics diagnostics.

Also, these practices where realized at the Institute of Physics:

- Winter practice: "Optical diagnostics in dense transient plasmas" July 2014
- Summer practice: "Transient atmospheric plasmas with applications in industry and medicine" January 2015

Assistantship at Laboratory and Tutor

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

March 2015 - November 2019

Assistantship at Laboratory, Institute of Physics: "Physics for science" (FIS109), "Thermodynamics" (FIS152), "Electricity and Magnetism" (FIS0153) and "Electronics for Physicists" (FIZ3300).

Tutor, Institute of Physics: "Introduction to Programming" (IIC1103) - 2015

Science communicator

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

March 2015 - November 2016

Worked in several science, technology, and university fairs.

Awards

Undergraduate Research Fund

Santiago, Chile

Pontifical Catholic University of Chile

Winter 2014 and Summer 2015

Two different awards for paid internships. Research done about "Optical diagnostics in Dense Transient Plasmas" (Winter 2014) and "Atmospheric plasmas" (Summer 2015)

Participation in projects or research programs.....

Monolith Controversies

Santiago, Chile

National Council of Culture and the Arts (Chile)

November 2013 - July 2014

Chilean Pavilion at the 14th Venice Architecture Biennale. Developed a system for audiovisual media for the pavilion.

The Chilean Pavilion was awarded with the Silver Lion.

Achievements

o Winner at BRAIN (Business, Research, Acceleration and Innovation) Chile.

Khapto was one of the 10 awarded startups between 325 scientific & technology projects. August, 2016. Santiago, Chile.

o International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) contestant.

Selected to represent Chile at the IOI in 2008 (El Cairo, Egypt) and 2009 (Plovdiv, Bulgaria).

 1st Place in VI IEEE Chilean Robotics Competition in Open Category November, 2007. Monterrey, Mexico.

 1st Place in VI IEEE Chilean Robotics Competition in Open Category October, 2007. Santiago, Chile.

Skills

- **Programming languages, syntaxes and/or libraries:** C/C++, Python, Matlab, Arduino, HTML, Javascript, ES6, SQL, MySQL, PHP, LaTeX, openFrameworks, LibCinder, React Native, CUDA, OpenCV, scikit-learn.
- Software: Visual Studio, Matlab, Origin (OriginLab), Xcode, LTspice, Microsoft Office, Rhinoceros 3D, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Git, Eagle.
- o Technical skills: 3D printing, CNC fabrication, PCBA design and fabrication, mathematical modeling.
- o Languages: Advanced English (IELTS: 7), Native Spanish.

Work experience

Map developer Santiago, Chile

United Nations Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean

2020

Development of a web geographic data viewer, including 4 types of data: segregation, mobility, migrations and general indicators. The work included geographic data processing, classification and visualization.

Map and data visualization developer

Stockholm, Sweden (Remote work)

ArkDes 201. Development of a interactive world map with the history of prefabricated panels for the "Flying Panels" exhibition.

A second interactive app was developed where users can select a building design to see a 3D visualization.

CTO
Santiago, Chile
Khapto
May 2016 - present

Startup which objective is to improve the way physiotherapy is realized. Through the use of different sensors in a wearable device, we provide the professional with a series of critical data that allow a more effective improvement of the patient. This, in a larger scale, will allow massive studies about injuries and treatments.

Programming and mathematics consultant

Santiago, Chile

o Dirección de Extensión y Servicios Externos (DESE) Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Estudios Urbanos UC July 2017 - August 2017

Advice on the development of software that automatically generates, through Monte-Carlo simulations, the average price of different types of buildings. The software was developed for the Internal Revenue Service of Chile.

Hardware and software developer

Santiago, Chile

Freelancer

2015

Design and development of a remote water level system for irrigation channel. An ultra-sensitive capacitive sensor was developed and through GSM the data was sent to a web server in order to be visualized in a website.

Interactive mobile app developer

Santiago, Chile

Dirección de Extensión y Servicios Externos (DESE)
 Facultad de Arquitectura, Diseño y Estudios Urbanos UC

March 2015 - August 2015

Development of a solution for the National Monuments Council of Chile consisting in a hybrid mobile App to register properties and national monuments, with a web-based management capable of generate automated reports.

Interactive Software developer

Santiago, Chile

Guillermo Acuña Arquitectos Asociados

September 2012 - April 2013

Design and development of an interactive software for an exhibition in the MAXXI museum, Rome.

The project proposes to visualize data about the city of Santiago on which a project of optimization of energies is proposed. As part of the team I developed all the software, visualizations and data analysis.

Interactive software & hardware developer and experience designer

Santiago, Chile

| Frankenstudio | Etnolab SpA

2011-2012

Responsible of the development of software and hardware for several projects and designing of interactive experiences. Some of the works includes:

- Interactive video wall with body recognition
- Educative game with on touch-screen
- Interactive installation with natural interaction using hand recognition and 3D capture
- Installation in museum on digital platforms
- Interactive installation in public street with web interaction
- Design and building of hardware

Web developer Santiago, Chile

Freelancer

2009–2011

Development of several websites and programming of an own CMS (Content Management System) to provide an easier management. Worked with PHP, MySQL, JS, HTML y CSS.

Projects

Hip implant classifier

Santiago, Chile

Project

2017

Development of software for hip implant classification, using TensorFlow.

Map scraper

Santiago, Chile

Project

2017

Web map scraper from a Web Map Server using OpenCV.